Guide to the Laura (Riding) Jackson and Schuyler B. Jackson collection, 1924-1991
Jackson, Laura (Riding) and Schuyler B., 1924-1991
- Series III. Correspondence
  - A) Laura (Riding) Jackson
    - Outgoing
      - June-July 1973 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Aug. 1973 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Sept. 1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Oct.-Nov. 1973 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Dec. 1973-Jan. 1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - [includes application for Guggenheim Fellowship], Feb.-Mar. 1974 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Apr.-May 1974 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - June-July 1974 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Aug. 1974 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Sept. 1974 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Nov.-Dec. 1974 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Jan.-Feb. 1974 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Jan.-Apr. 1975 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - May.-June 1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - July -Aug. 1975 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Sept. 1975 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Oct. 1975 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Nov.-Dec. 1975 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Jan.-Feb. 1976 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Mar. 1976 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Apr.-May 1976 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - June-July 1976 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Aug.-Sept. 1976 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Oct.-Nov. 1976 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Dec. 1976-Feb. 1977 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Mar.-Apr. 1977 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - May-June 1977 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - July-Sept. 1977 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Oct.-Dec. 1977 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Jan.-Apr. 1978 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - May-Aug. 1978 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Sept.-Dec. 1978 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Jan.-Apr. 1979 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - May-Sept. 1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Oct.-Dec. 1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Jan.-Mar. 1980 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Apr.-July 1980 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Aug.-Dec. 1980 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Jan.-Mar. 1981 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Apr.-July 1981 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Aug.-Oct. 1981 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Nov. 1981-Mar. 1982 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Apr.-Sept. 1982 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Oct. 1982-July 1983 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - July 1983-Feb. 1984 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Mar.-Aug. 1984 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Sept. 1984-Feb. 1985 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Mar.-July 1985 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Aug.-Dec. 1985 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Jan.-June 1986 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - July-Dec. 1986 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Jan.-Nov. 1987 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Dec. 1987-May 1989 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - B) Schuyler B. Jackson
    - Incoming
      - 1924-Aug. 1943, [includes undated letter from Robert Frost with explanatory note by SBJ] (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Apr. 1956-Mar. 1964 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - May 1964-June 1968 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing
      - Jan. 1940-Aug. 1943 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - May 1960-June 1968 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - C)Formerly Restricted Correspondence
    - E.M. (Sally) Chilver
      - SC to L(R)J, ca. 1939; 1945-1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - SC to L(R)J, 1978-79 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - SC to L(R)J, 1980-83 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - SC to L(R)J, 1984-87 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - (postcards), 1988-89 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to SC, May 1936-Sept. 1979 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to SC, Oct. 1979-Dec. 1986 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Alan Clark
      - AC to L(R)J, 1970-73 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1979-80 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1981-83 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1984-85 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - AC to L(R)J, 1987-1990 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1970-72 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1974-78 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to AC, Jan.-June 1975 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to AC, July-Dec. 1975 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to AC, Jan.-June 1976 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to AC, July-Dec. 1976 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - L(R)J to AC, Jan.-June 1977 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to AC, July-Dec. 1977 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1979-1980 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1981-84 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to AC, 1985-86 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Grace Friedberg
      - GF to L(R)J, Dec. 1963-Dec. 1976 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - GF to L(R)J, Jan. 1977-Nov. 1989 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to GF, June 1967-May 1986 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Elizabeth Friedmann
      - EF to L(R)J, Jan. 1980-Dec. 1986 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - EF to L(R)J, Jan. 1987-Mar. 1989 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to EF, Jan. 1981-Nov. 1988 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - EF to others, Feb. 1988-Mar. 1992 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - To EF from others, Mar. 1988-Apr. 1988 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - John Guggenheim Memorial Foundation/James Mathias
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Jan.-July 1976 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Aug.-Dec. 1976 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Jan.-June 1978 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, July-Oct. 1978 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Nov.-Dec. 1978 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Jan.-July 1979 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, Aug.-Dec. 1979 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Guggenheim/Mathias to L(R)J, 1982-1987 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, Jan.-Dec. 1976 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, Jan.-June 1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, July-Oct. 1977 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, Nov. 1977-July 1978 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, Aug. 1978-Apr. 1979 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, May 1979-June 1980 (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, July 1980-Apr. 1981 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, May 1981-May 1982 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to Guggenheim Foundation/Mathias, June 1982-July 1987 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - James Mathias to others, Feb. 17, 1980 and Aug. 27, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Others to James Mathias, June 25, 1979, Feb. 20, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - William Harmon
      - WH to L(R)J, Mar. 1985-Dec. 1989 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - WH to L(R)J, Jan. 1984-Feb. 1985 (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - L(R)J to WH, Feb. 1984-Dec. 1986 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Mark Jacobs
      - MJ to L(R)J, Mar. 1970-Dec. 1974 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - MJ to L(R)J, Jan. 1975-Mar. 1977 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - MJ to L(R)J, Apr. 1977-June 1978 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - MJ to L(R)J, July 1978-Aug. 1979 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - MJ to L(R)J, Sept. 1979-Oct. 1984 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to MJ, May 1972-July 1975 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to MJ, Aug. 1975-Mar. 1977 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to MJ, Apr. 1977-Oct. 1978 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to MJ, Nov. 1978-Feb. 1979 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to MJ, Oct. 1984 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Mr. Jacobs to others [to the editor of The Guardian], Nov. 7, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Katharine Townsend Jackson
      - KTJ to L(R)J [Includes copy of a reply written by L(R)J to KTJ, Jan. 10, 1969], undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Richard Mayers
      - RM to L(R)J, Oct. 1963-Jan. 1986 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to RM, June 1965-Feb. 1986 The Jewish Committee for Personal Service to Mr. and Mrs. Mayers, Sept. 17, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Isabel Mayers
      - To Isabel Mayers from her mother, Sadie Edersheim Reichenthal, n.d. ["Attempted transcript of a letter from Laura Riding to her sister Isabel..., Canellun, May 6, 1933] (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Katherine McCagg
      - McCagg, Katherine to L(R)J [includes letters from various McCagg family members], July 24, 1968-Dec. 3, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to McCagg, Feb. 25, 1969-Apr. 12, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - John Nolan
      - JN to L(R)J, Jan. 1977-Oct. 1989 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to JN, May 1984-Dec. 1986 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Robert and Judith Nye
      - RN to L(R)J, June 1962-Feb. 1965 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - RN to L(R)J, Mar. 1965-July 1965 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - RN to L(R)J, Aug. 1965-Jan. 1990 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to RN, May 1963-Feb. 1965 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to RN, Mar. 1965-Aug. 1965 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - L(R)J to RN, Sept. 1965-Sept. 1966 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Schuyler B. Jackson to Robert and Judith Nye Robert Nye to Schuyler B. Jackson, Aug. 30, 1965-Aug. 6, 19661965?; Jan. 14, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Griselda Ohannessian
      - GO to L(R)J [Carbons of L(R)J's responses are stapled to several of Griselda Ohannessian's letters], ca. 1955-May 1973 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - GO to L(R)J, Sept. 1973-Nov. 1989 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to GO, Jan. 1945-Nov. 1982 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Mary and Peter Oliver
      - Oliver to L(R)J, Feb. 1967-June 1972 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Oliver to L(R)J, Sept. 1972-Sept. 1976 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Oliver to L(R)J, Dec. 1976-Sept. 1980 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Oliver to L(R)J, Oct. 1980-Sept. 1983 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Oliver to L(R)J, Oct. 1983-Jan. 1987 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to Oliver, Aug. 1968-July 1976 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - L(R)J to Oliver, Oct. 1976-Oct. 1985 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Maria Jackson Parker
      - MJP to L(R)J, Mar. 1940-Dec. 1974 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - MJP to L(R)J, Jan. 1975-Dec. 1985 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - MJP to L(R)J, May 1986-July 2, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to MJP, July 1968-Sept. 1987 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Sonia Raiziss to Laura (Riding) Jackson and to Schuyler B. Jackson
      - SR to L(R)J, July 1961-Dec. 1964 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1965-Dec. 1966 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1967-Nov. 1968 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1969-Nov. 1970 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1971-Dec. 1972 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1973-Feb. 1976 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - SR to L(R)J, Apr. 1976-Dec. 1978 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - SR to L(R)J, Jan. 1979-Aug. 1989 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to SR [includes letter of uncertain authorship], Mar. 1962-Mar. 1966 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to SR, Apr. 1966-Oct. 1967 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to SR, Nov. 1967-Oct. 1968 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to SR, Nov. 1968-Dec. 1969 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to SR, Jan.-Dec. 1970 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to SR, Jan.-Dec. 1971 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - L(R)J to SR, Jan. 1972-May 1973 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to SR, June 1973-Apr. 1975 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - L(R)J to SR, May. 1975-July 1976 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to SR, Aug. 1976-Aug. 1986, See also: Chelsea (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Robert Reichenthal (aka Robert Ritchey)
      - Reichenthal, Robert to L(R)J, Dec. 15, 1933-Dec. 1972 (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Reichenthal, Robert to L(R)J, July 1975-Sept. 9, 1984 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - L(R)J to Robert Reichenthal, Oct. 29, 1963-Aug. 1984 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Eric and Margaret Rideal
      - Rideal to L(R)J, Aug. 1962-June 24, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to Rideal, Nov. 6, 1968-Dec. 16, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Gertrude Stein
      - [L(R)J commentary on her correspondence with Gertrude Stein, ts., 11pp.; letters from L(R)J to Gertrude Stein are not in the collection] GS to L(R)J, undated, ca. 1927-1929 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - James Tyler
      - JT to L(R)J, Oct. 1979-Dec. 1983 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - JT to L(R)J, Jan. 1984-Dec. 1985 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - JT to L(R)J, Jan. 1985-Dec. 1987 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - JT to L(R)J, Feb. 1988-Aug. 1989 JT to Ivan Ruzicka, Nov. 20, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to JT, Nov. 1979-Nov. 1986 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Joyce Wexler
      - L(R)J to JW, Feb.-Mar. 1972 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Joan and Theodore Wilentz
      - Wilentz, Joan and Theodore to L(R)J, Mar. 1973-Dec. 1977 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Wilentz, Joan and Theodore to L(R)J, Jan. 1978-Dec.1983 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Wilentz, Joan and Theodore to L(R)J, Jan. 1984-Dec. 1985 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Wilentz, Joan and Theodore to L(R)J, Jan. 1986-Dec. 1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - L(R)J to Joan and Theodore Wilentz, Apr. 1973-Nov. 1977 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - L(R)J to Joan and Theodore Wilentz, Feb. 1978-May 1987 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Postcards from Wilentz to L(R)J, 1970-1990 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Schuyler B. Jackson to and from his children
      - from Schuyler [and often Laura] to his children in young age, incoming and outgoing, mostly undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Ben and Mary Jackson to and from Schuyler and Laura. Includes letters between Laura and Benjamin after Schuyler's death, 1963-1972 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - to and from SBJ's children, several undated; 1965-1968 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - to SBJ from Katharine Townsend Jackson, n.d.; ca. 1940, 1949 (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Literary Manuscripts
  - Published Works
    - Major Works
      - Anarchism is not Enough (1928), [excerpt from Anarchism Is Not Enough] pp. 54-57, photocopy (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Experts Are Puzzled (1930), "An Address to America" ts. 2pp. photocopy pp. 135-152 + note ms. 1p. (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Pictures (1933), "Pictures" 8pp. n.d. photocopy (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - The Covenant of Literal Morality (1938), "The Covenant of Literal Morality. Protocol I Preliminary Questions" ts. 1p. + note ms. 1p. (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Len Lye and the Problem of Popular Film (1938), "Len Lye and the Problem of Popular Film" [Literal solutions] pp. 1-46 photocopy (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - The World and Ourselves (1938), "A Personal Letter with a request for a reply" 2 ts. 4pp. gestetner, Jan. 1937 (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - The World and Ourselves, [Introduction to University Microfilm reprint of The World and Ourselves] ms. 38pp. Aug. 1969 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - The Telling (1972), "The Telling: The Original" ts. 33pp.; ms. 17pp., ca. 1967 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - The Telling, "Final plans except for dedication revised as per the second one here given" ts. 19pp. Photocopy of ts. of "Preface for a Second Reading" and preliminary pages, Oct. 2, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - The Telling, "Original of my Preface for a Second Reading, in the book The Telling, written to be a preface (coming at the beginning of book, then rewritten, joined with "Preface for a Second Reading" and to follow the main Telling text in the book"; "Preface," ts., xiv, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - The Telling, "Mainly typescript of supplementary portion of The Telling, from which printing was done (back-printing) with a little correspondence on the text, mainly the supplementary section, with Mr. A.G. Dewey of the Athlone Press" pp. 131-188, corrected in pencil; pp.103-162, ca. 1971 (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - The Telling, "Preface for a second reading" ts. pp. 50-67 Oct. 2, 1968 "Some After-Speaking: Private Words" ts. pp. 10-102 Letter to Athlone Press ts. 8pp. Sept. 25, 1971 [concerns The Telling]; See also: Athlone Press (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - The Telling, "Part III. Private Words" ms. 100pp., 1971 (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - The Telling, ["Part III. Private Words"] "very untidy basic script" ms. pp. 101-133, 2 ms. index cards "Some Notes" ms. 75pp. "Notes" ts.1p. "no copy of these ms. pages" ms. 1p. Aug. 24, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - The Telling, "Papers relevant to The Telling" [original table of contents of folder] ms. 1p. "Preface for Chelsea [20/21]," ts. 1p. carbon [note] ms., 1p. [corrections sent to the editors of Chelsea] ts. 7pp. carbon "Preface to This Printing" ts. 3pp. carbon; [dedication] ts. 1p. "Preface" ts. pp. i-xiv carbon "The Telling" ts. pp. 13-33 + introductory material ts. 3pp.; ms. 1p. (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - The Telling, [Clippings saved by L(R)J pertaining to The Telling] (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - Four Unposted Letters to Catherine (1993), [Uncorrected galley proof (1993) pp.1-78; master set second pass, pp.1-80; photocopy of dedication, ts. 1p.] (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - The Word Woman and Other Related Writings (1993), [Letter from Persea Books to Elizabeth Friedmann, n.d.; book jacket, photograph; "The Word Woman and Other Related Writings" ts. i-vii, pp.1-151] (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - The Word Woman, "The Word Woman" [cont] ts. pp. 152-216 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - The Word Woman, "The Word Woman" [cont] ts. 116pp. photocopy (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning: A New Foundation for the Definition of Words, ms. material [paged draft interspersed with lengthy notes and comments] explanatory note by L(R)J ts. 1p; dedication, ts. 1p.; Ch. I ms. pp.1-25; Ch. II, ms. pp. 1-27, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. III ms. pp.1-21; Part Two introductory matter ms. 3pp. "Foreward" ms. 6pp.; Ch. IV ms. 34pp. (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. V ms. pp. 1-23 and (2) 1-24; Ch. VI ms. pp. 1-13 (2) pp. 1-23 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Rational Meaning, Part Three, Ch. VII ms. pp. 1-13; (2) pp. 1-21; (2) pp. 1-8 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning, "Foreward to Part Three" ms. pp.1-4; Ch. VIII ms. pp.1-40 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. VIII (cont.) additional notes ms. pp. 1-9; revisions ts. 5pp. and ms. pp. 1-19; additional notes ms. and ts. 39pp.; Ch. IX ms. pp. 1-22 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. IX (cont.) (3) ms. pp. 1-22; (4) ms. pp. 1-18; (5) ms. pp.1-8; appendix ms. pp. 1-5 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Rational Meaning, Explanatory note ms. 1p.; "Introduction" ["Rough draft of Introduction to Rational Meaning by L. J., 1972"] ms. pp. 1-34 "Foreword" ms. pp. 1-5; Ch. X ms. pp. 1-82 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XI ms. pp. 1-58 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XII ms. pp. 1-76 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XIII ms. pp. 1-77 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XIV ms. pp. 1-60 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XV ms. pp. 1-90 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Rational Meaning, Part VI, Ch. XVI ms. pp. 1-24; (4) ms. pp.1-9; Ch. XVII ms. pp. 1-16; (4) ms. pp. 1-28; (4) ms. pp. 1-11; ms. pp. 1-6; (5) ms. pp. 1-6 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning, Part VI, Ch. XVIII ms. pp. 1-21; ms. pp.1-25; ms. pp. 1-41; ms. pp. 1-43 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Rational Meaning, Ch. XX (?) ms. pp. 20-39; (5) ms. pp. 1-25; (6) ms. pp. 1-22; Ch. XXI ms. pp. 1-18; (3) ms. pp. 1-27; (4) ms. pp. 1-13; (5) ms. pp. 1-23 plus additional notes ms. 8pp. (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Rational Meaning, "The New Grammar," [essay for Rational Meaning] ms. 137pp. (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, [Supplementary materials for Rational Meaning] ms. ca. 200pp. (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Rational Meaning, Drafts of various parts, including portions of Ch. XIX, various paginations ms. ca. 200pp. (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Rational Meaning, Various drafts of prefatory materials and "concluding speculations" ms. ca. 100pp. (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning, Notes for Rational Meaning, ms ca. 100pp. (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, Typescript material from Rational Meaning: "Foreword" ts. 9pp. carbon; "Epigraph" ts. 1p. carbon 1967 "First Preface" ts. xxi pp. carbon 1973 "Second Preface" ts. pp. xxii-xxx carbon 1976 "Third Preface" ts. pp. xxxi-xxxlv 1985; ts. xxxi-xxxlv carbon Ch. II ts. pp. 11-24; Ch. III ts. pp. 25-42 carbon (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Rational Meaning, "R [ational] M[eaning]-Notes of Comment" Ch. III p. 26 ts 1p., n.d. (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part II: The Use of Words: The Apparatus of Guidance" (Chapters IV-VI) ts. pp. 44-104 carbon (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part III: Language and Rationality" (Chapters VII-IX) ts. pp. 105-183 carbon (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part IV: The Principle of Definition" (Chapters X-XII) ts. pp. 184-281 carbon (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part V: The Make-up of Language" (Chapters XIII-XV) ts. pp. 282-383a carbon (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part VI: Studies in Meaning-Relation And Meaning-Distinction" (Chapters XVI-XVIII) ts. pp. 384-488 carbon (some pages original) (Box 82, Folder 8)
      - Rational Meaning, "Part VII: The Future Tasks" (Ch. XIX) ts. pp. 487-563 carbon (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Rational Meaning, [notes for correction of ts.] ms. 15pp. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Poems
      - "A bundle of poems in typescript-originals, most later printed with revisions" [note on envelope in L(R)J's hand], n.d. "Dear Growth," "Fine Fellow Son of a Poor Fellow," "Love at a Sickbed," "I Know a Self-Love," "Untaken Image," "Sea, False Philosophy," "And Nature Has a Crop," "Happy Possessor and Industrious Spirit," "Carnival of Numbers," "By Crude Rotation," "Ode to The Triumph of Bodily Intelligence," "Then Wherefore," "Apology for Time, Self, Love, Earnestness and Disaffection," "Midsummer Duet 1934" [by Laura Riding and Robert Graves], "Doom in Bloom," "Seizure of the World" ts. 32pp. (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - "For One Who Will Believe" and "For All Our Sakes" clipping [from The Nation, 123, August 11, 1926] (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - "How I Called the Ant Darling" Two Worlds. II (December 6, 1926) p. 114 photocopy (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - "The Second Leaf" 2pp. [privately printed]; ts 6pp., ca. 1934 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - "The Judgement" Poetry Pilot (September 1970) p. 5 [original issue]; commentary ts. 3pp. (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - "In Gratuitous Witness" London Review of Books, Vol. 17 (Sept. 7, 1975) ts. 2pp. carbon (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - "Lamenting the Terms of Modern Praise" Chelsea, 46 (1988) ts. 1p. and 2 ts. 3pp. carbon (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - [Early poems included in PN Review, 78 Special Supplement (March 1991)] "The Spider" ts. 2pp.; "To this Death" ts. 1p.; "The Twins" ts. 1p.; "Against Adventure" ts. 2pp.; "An Ancient Revisits" ts. 1p.; "Brothers" ts. 1p.; "But Lies" ts. 1p.; "The Fourth Estate" ts. 1p.; "Grieve, Women" ts. 1p.; "The Haunt" ts. 1p.; "Joravaly" ts. 1p.; "Song of the Lyre" ts. 1p.; "The Subterfuge" ts. 4pp.; "Invocation for Birds" ts. 3pp.; "A City Seems" ts. 1p.; "Doomed" ts. 1p.; "A Preface" ts. 1p.; "Trifle" ts. 1p.; "Truth" ts. 2 pp.; "If a Woman Should Be Messiah" ts. 2pp.; "Harlequinade on a Curbstone" ts. 7pp. (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Essays and Articles
      - "Laura Riding" New Verse. Answers to an Enquiry, no. 11 (October 1934) pp. 3-5. Also includes responses by Robert Graves, Louis Macneice, Wyndham Lewis, Roy Campbell, Norman Cameron, and Wallace Stevens (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - ["The following paragraphs are from the authors' review of Webster's Dictionary of Synonyms published in Library Bulletin, November 1942"] pp. 345, 225, cuttings (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - "The following is a sequel of 1964 to my story A First Lesson in Geography..." Antaeus (1965), photocopy (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - "Comments on The Fable of the Dice and on my work since 1938..." ts. 1p. Dec. 14, 1971 "On The Fable of the Dice" Goldsmith, Maurice, ed. The Predicament Of Man: An Examination Of Policies For The Future (Frimley: Inforlink Ltd. [for] Science Policy Foundation, 1972) ts. 3pp. Dec. 16, 1971 (Box 83, Folder 14)